# Jorge Ortiz

Mayaguez, Puerto Rico



jorge.ortiz41@upr.edu



7876644744



linkedin.com/in/jorgeaortizramirez

#### **Summary**

Software engineering student with 5 years of software development experience and 3 years in full-stack web development. Well-versed in python data science frameworks, MERN stack for web development, and documentation for the software development lifecycle. Increased data accessibility and improved user experience at the Arecibo Observatory with a full-stack web app. Using exploratory data analysis I uncovered the most critical regions and demographics affected by the 2020 earthquakes in Puerto Rico.

#### **Experience**

#### Software Engineer

The Arecibo Observatory

May 2022 - Aug 2022 (4 months)

Created a full stack web application by myself with the guidance of a mentor to show real-time data from the 12m Radio Telescope and a logging tool to collect operational data.

### Software Engineer

Agricultural Extension Service UPRM

Sep 2021 - Present (1 year +)

Develop web modules using PHP/Laravel/MySQL for the different services the organization offers. (Work-Study)

#### Bartender

Barril Sin Fondo

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021 (4 months)

Work as a team to serve drinks, food, and clean up in an efficient manner to increase the client's experience and get them to recommend the place.

#### correlation: Data Analyst

Correlation One

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021 (5 months)

- "Our program, taught by instructors from top universities like Harvard and MIT, is an immersive 13week training program in practical data skills."
- 500 out of 8000 applicants were selected
- Learned to use modern data science techniques and methods using real world cases from companies.

## Data Analyst

Voluntariado de Ingenieros y Profesionales

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021 (6 months)

responsible for cleaning, organizing and analyzing data to derive useful insights and deliver a dashboard with data

#### **Education**



#### University of Puerto Rico-Mayaguez

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2018 - 2023

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Project Management 101 - The Arecibo Observatory



**Data Science Orientation** - Coursera

#### **Skills**

MERN Stack • Software Documentation • Project Management • JavaScript • React.js • MongoDB • Web Development • Web Design • Machine Learning • Data Analysis